本字幕由网络爱好者联盟原创翻译
欢迎加入我们 www.ZiMuZu.pub
在保留译者名单的前提下任何人不需要经得我们的同意
可用本字幕做任何用途因此所产生的后果由您自行承担
{\clip(201,214,201,216)\t(0,600,2,\clip(110,214,292,216))\t(4200,4800,2,\clip(201,214,201,216))}■
{\clip(80,216,392,216)\t(600,1000,2,\clip(80,192,392,240))\t(4200,4600,2,\clip(80,216,392,216))}翻\h译
Charles#Zhang\h\h\h\h低调付付\h\h\h\h左派青年\h\h\h\hsummer_j2000\h\h\h\h忌廉喵的小仙女\h\h\h\h为小李子拔刀
{\clip(201,214,201,216)\t(0,600,2,\clip(60,214,392,216))\t(4200,4800,2,\clip(201,214,201,216))}■
{\clip(60,216,392,216)\t(600,1000,2,\clip(60,192,392,240))\t(4200,4600,2,\clip(60,216,392,216))}翻\h译
圆周率lfy\h\h\h\h不用霸王辛道长\h\h\h\hraptor05\h\h\h\h不要辣不要麻不要香菜不要葱\h\h\h\h扒虾爬子大师\h\h\h\h我要头发不要校对
{\clip(201,214,201,216)\t(0,600,2,\clip(150,214,252,216))\t(4200,4800,2,\clip(201,214,201,216))}■
{\clip(110,216,292,216)\t(600,1000,2,\clip(110,192,292,240))\t(4200,4600,2,\clip(110,216,292,216))}校对\h&\h后期
吃薯条不想蘸酱\h\h\h\h大红
{\clip(62,224,336,224)\t(1000,1400,2,\clip(62,204,336,224))\t(7600,8000,\clip(62,224,336,224))}片头推广合作洽谈：请联系普罗米修斯邮箱 PLMXS2016@GmaiL.com
妈妈  快点  是时候开放神奇乐园了
Mom, come on. It's time to open the park.
哦对  我们开始吧
Oh, right. Here we go.
又是神奇乐园里的一天
It was another day in Wonderland,
史上最妙不可言的华丽游乐园
the most splendiferous amusement park ever.
皮纳特要建新的过山车吗
And Peanut was creating a new ride?
还没呢
Not yet.
首先  吉祥物们正准备打开大门
First, the mascots were getting ready to open the gates.
各位早上好  我们开始吧
All right, guys. Good morning! Let's do it!
现在  大家都靠过来
Now, everyone, bring it in.
人们喜欢来神奇乐园
People love coming to Wonderland
因为在这里能享受最欢乐的时光
because it's the best time ever.
多亏有了你们
And that's thanks to you.
因为你们是
Because who are you?
我们是神奇乐园的奇迹
We are the wonder in Wonderland.
我听不见哦
I can't hear you.
我们是神奇乐园的奇迹
We are the wonder in Wonderland.
再来一次
One more time.
我们是神奇乐园的奇迹
We are the wonder in Wonderland!
没错  就是这样
Yes, you are!
最后一个到达齿轮秋千的人是烂鳄梨
Last one to Clockwork Swings is a rotten avocado!
谁想来拨动开关呀
Who wants to flip the switch?
-你来吧  哥们  -不  你来吧
Why don't you go ahead, brother? No, you go, brother.
不不不  你来
No, no, no, no, you go.
要不你们俩一起动手  怎么样
How about you both flip it?
欢迎欢迎  这将会是美好的一天
Welcome! Boy, it's gonna be a great day.
因为从乐园打开的那一刻起
I know that because we've had literally nothing but wondrous days
在这里度过的每一分钟都会无比奇妙
since the moment we opened!
你们有听过脱水的笑话吗
Did you hear the joke about dehydration?
没有
No.
没错  因为脱水这件事
That's right, because there is absolutely
完全没有笑点
nothing funny about dehydration.
去吧
Go along!
葛蕾塔  我们能和你合个影吗
Greta! Can we take a picture with you?
当然了  过来  过来
Of course. Come in, come in, come in.
好的  准备好了吗
Okay, ready?
一  二  三  哼噜
One, two, three, snort!
格斯  库珀  跷跷板二号没有在动
Gus! Cooper! Teeter number two isn't tottering.
-包在我们身上  -收到
- We're on it. - Copy that.
海狸双胞胎兄弟  出动
Beaver twin brothers, activate!
-尾巴对对拍  库珀  -哈哈
- Tail slap, Coop. - Ha-ha!
快看  是他
Look, it's him!
大家早上好哇
Whoo! Good morning, everyone!
你们太棒了
You're splendiferous!
皮纳特  嗨  皮纳特
Peanut! Hi, Peanut!
感谢你们出来游玩
Thanks for coming out.
你们这群人长得可真漂亮
You're a great-looking group.
今天将会是神奇之地的奇迹之日
Today's gonna be filled with the wonder
而这片神奇之地就是
of this wonderful land we call
神奇乐园
Wonderland!
看看他  他可真讨喜
Look at him. He's so charming!
还能说会道
Such a way with words.
好了各位  谁想看皮纳特
All right, folks, who here wants to see Peanut
坐上全新的空中战机
ride the brand new SkyFlinger?
太妙了
Terrific!
这里还有空位吗
Room for one more in this SkyFlinger?
你得坐稳了  孩子
You might want to hold on, kid.
-嗨  -嗨
- Hi! - Hey!
-你拿到神奇猩猩了吗  -没呢
- Have you pick up your WonderChimp doll yet? - No.
那还等什么呢  快来吧
Well, what are you waiting for? Come on!
神奇猩猩就在这里  嗒哒
And here are the WonderChimps. Ha!
有5200种造型可供选择
5,200 different outfits to pick from.
太太太棒啦
Splen-diddy-doo!
你太棒啦
You're splendiferous!
你今天要创造什么呢  皮纳特
What are you creating today, Peanut?
是的  没错
Oh, yes, that's right!
今天我们要开放旋转木马
Today is the day we're opening the carousel.
它是一个绝世美人儿
Oh, and she's gonna be a real beaut.
我用了最好的纯种马
I've got the finest thoroughbred horses...
说真的嘛
Really?
听上去有点老调重弹了
That sounds kinda been there, done that.
我们可以想个更好的
I think we can do better.
你说得对
And You're right.
我觉得皮纳特能造个更好的
I think Peanut deserves better.
你来想一个吧  妈妈
You come up with it, Mom!
我可得听听这位年轻远见家的意见
How could I not defer to the young visionary
她可是想出了空中战机呢
who came up with "The SkyFlinger"?
嘿  别取笑我  我那时才五岁
Hey, don't make fun of me. I was only five.
我不是在取笑你  小傻瓜
I wasn't making fun of you, silly.
我只是喜欢听你出主意
I just like it when the ideas come from you.
现在  想一想
Now, think.
皮纳特应该在旋转木马上放什么动物
What kind of animal should Peanut put on your carousel?
-鱼  -随便什么鱼吗
- Fish! - Just like any fish?
会飞的鱼
Flying fish!
推动鱼鳍的时候  鱼就会动起来
And when you push the fin, the fish will come to life.
它们可以飞遍整个乐园
And you could fly them all over the park.
正好说到点子上了  琼
Ooh, now we're talking, June.
好
Okay,
你只需要把记号笔给皮纳特
all you have to do is give Peanut his marker,
然后悄悄告诉皮纳特
and whisper your wish into Peanut's ear.
皮纳特  我们想要你做的就是
Now, Peanut, here's what we want you to do.
在神奇乐园里真的可以做到
You really can do that in Wonderland.
做旋转木马  但不是用马
Make a carousel, but instead of horses... Hmm?
而是用飞鱼
make flying fish.
好的
Okay.
妙笔快生花
Splendiferous.
你今天想去哪儿呢
Where would you like to go today?
谢谢你  不管你是谁
Thank you, whoever you are,
无论你来自哪里
wherever you come from.
当鱼掠过小吃摊的时候
And when the fish fly through the concession stand,
人们会把爆米花扔到空中喂它们
people will throw popcorn in the air to feed them.
只要布莫不先把爆米花吃完的话
So long as Boomer doesn't eat all the popcorn first.
好了  琼  该睡觉了
Okay, June, time for bed.
哦不
Oh, no!
再等一会儿好吗  拜托
A little longer? Please?
不行  你明天还要上学呢
Nope, you've got school tomorrow.
如果我们再不认真对待的话
And you've got a DVR that's gonna
你的录像机的存储空间就快满了
run out of storage unless we start getting serious.
-但是  -别  别怪通信员
- Oh, but... - No, don't blame the messenger.
我要着手删除一些东西了
I am just gonna have to start making some very aggressive deletes.
你个讨厌的家伙
You stinker.
好吧  小琼琼  今晚就到这了
Okay, June Bug, that's it for tonight.
妈妈
Um, Mom,
你觉得神奇乐园是真实存在的吗
do you ever feel like Wonderland is real?
或者可能是真的
Or maybe it could be?
当然有可能
Of course it could be.
真的吗  你怎么知道
Really? How do you know?
因为我认识那个创造出神奇乐园的女孩
Because I know the girl who imagined it
她什么都可以做到
and she can do anything.
-我吗  -是呀
- Me? - Oh, yeah.
晚安  小琼琼
Good night, June Bug.
明天是个大日子  伙计们
Big day tomorrow, guys.
是时候让神奇乐园变成真的了
Hmm... Time to make Wonderland real.
早上好  琼·贝利
Good morning, June Bailey.
班基  就是今天了
Banky, today is the day.
摩天环车工程开工啦
Operation Loop-De-Loop is a go!
但我还没喝早茶呢
But I haven't even had my morning coffee.
好极了
Splendiferous!
这个放在坡道下面  这个多拿一点
That goes under the ramp. Yeah, more of those.
这个丢掉也没关系  还需要多一点钉子
Eh, no one will miss that. We're gonna need more nails.
干得很棒  就是这样
Good job. Now, that's what I'm talking about!
干得漂亮
Great work.
他们说这是不可能成功的  但是看好了
They said it couldn't be done, but behold!
伟大奇迹
The Grand Wonder!
-谁说这不可能成功的  -他们
- Who said it couldn't be done? - They.
-他们是谁  -这只是种表达方式
- Who's "they"? - It's just an expression.
别抠字眼来拆我的台
Don't bust me on a technicality.
562英尺的滑道
562 feet of track!
带有虫洞的星际宇航基地
An intergalactic spaceport complete with wormhole!
而"pièce de résistance"
And pièce de résistance...
就是法语里超级棒的意思
That's French for "super awesome."
一个真正的摩天环车
a genuine loop-de-loop!
你刚说垂直落差有多高
Uh... How high did you say the vertical drop is?
48.8英尺
48.8 feet.
对没有概念的人来说就是14.87米
That's 14.87 meters for the uninitiated. Uh...
试运行启动
Commencing test run.
所有准备已就绪
All systems are a go. Uh...
-5 4 3 2 1  -咱能谈谈吗
- Five, four, three, two, one. - Can we talk about this?
发射员
Launcher!
点火发射
We have ignitialization!
不
Oh, no!
小桃的绳子掉了
Peaches is loose!
启动应急措施
Launching countermeasures.
哦  天哪
Oh... Oh, gosh.
启动涡轮发射器
Engage turbo launcher!
老公  你有看到我的手机吗
Honey, have you seen my cell phone?
打开宇航基地
Open the spaceport.
马上  马上  低头
I'm trying, I'm trying! Duck!
极速穿越黑洞
Warp speed through a black hole.
好了  准备停车了
Okay, ready to stop now.
不可能  高潮来了
No way! Time for the grand finale.
启动推进器
Firing thrusters!
刹车  刹车  刹车
Brake, brake, brake!
坏了  坏了  坏了
It broke, broke, broke.
注意  当心  不
Look out! Watch out, no!
给  用这个撬动左侧的推进器
Here. Use this to pry the thrusters on the left.
这不是方向盘吗
Isn't that the steering wheel?
本来是  动作快点
It was. Now hurry!
-没有用啊  -不要敲  用撬
- It's not working! - Don't bang. Pry, pry, pry!
-快点  快点  -我在努力  努力
- Hurry, hurry! - I'm trying, I'm trying!
琼  我爱你
I love you, June!
我还活着  感谢克利须那神
I'm alive! Thank Krishna.
克利须那神: 是印度教诸神中最广受崇拜的一位神祇，是诸神之首，世界之主
这真是
That was...
棒极了
awesome!
-有没有人录下来  -你们太厉害了
- Did anyone video that? -You guys rock!
下一个我来
I'm next!
嘿  我的栅栏怎么回事
Hey! What happened to my fence?
我的花园
Oh! My garden!
一个消防栓要这么多钱吗
That much for one fire hydrant?
我建议送去军事学校
My advice? Military school.
他们会教你女儿学该守的规矩
They'll drill home the kind of discipline your daughter needs.
不用担心  我们会惩罚她的  好吧
Don't you worry. She will be disciplined, all right.
你能行吗
You got this?
必须的  只要不用我去
If it means not having to be the one to try
跟我们可爱的疯女儿讲道理的话
and talk sense into our adorable lunatic of a daughter, you bet.
弗莱德  很高兴见到你  你妻子和
Fred! Good to see you. How are the wife and...
你想说军事学校的事吗
The thing about military school?
那些军事学校通常都很远
It's usually far away.
你肯定会非常想我的
Think about how much you'd miss me.
那样的话是谁受惩罚呢
Who would really be the one getting punished?
我们不会送你去军事学校
We're not sending you to military school.
-不会吗  -不会
- You're not? - Oh, no.
因为军事学校不会让你做
Because military school doesn't have nearly
接下来这么多的家务活
the amount of chores you're gonna be subjected to.
看来我是自己给自己挖了个坑
I guess I walked right into that one.
你到底在想什么  琼
What were you thinking, June?
你知不知道你有多走运
Do you know how lucky you are?
你可能会撞得不只是手上有淤青那么简单
Could have been a whole lot worse than a raspberry on your elbow.
你不是说神奇乐园可能是真的吗
I was just listening to you. You said Wonderland could be real.
还说我可以做成任何事情
And that I could do anything.
我并非想让你停止天马行空的自由想象
I never want you to stop using your imagination, June Bug.
但你也要切记想法要务实  行为要安全
But I need you to also remember to be practical and safe.
如果你出事  我该怎么办呢
I can't imagine what I'd do if something happened to you.
虽然我那样做是不对的
Even though I shouldn't have done it,
但你觉得我造出来的东西酷吗
did you think what I built was cool?
我怎么觉得并不重要
It doesn't matter what I think.
但是格斯和库珀肯定会大吃一惊
But Gus and Cooper, on the other hand, would've been crazy impressed.
是啊
Yeah.
但是史蒂夫会吓出心脏病的  是吧
But Steve would've had a heart attack, huh?
那是  当然了
Yes. Oh, yeah.
所以
So,
我们能继续建造神奇乐园吗
we can keep building more of Wonderland?
当然可以
Yes, of course.
但是你可不能再给邻居搞破坏了
But, June, without wrecking the neighborhood.
对  不给邻居搞破坏
Right, whithout wrecking the neighberhood.
太棒了
Yeah!
皮纳特  这是我们想让你做的
Now, Peanut, here's what we want you to do.
齿轮秋千是乐园的心脏
Clockwork Swings is the heart of the park.
齿轮秋千一打开  神奇乐园就会活过来
And when it turns on, Wonderland comes to life!
和宇航员琼一起在零重力空间漂浮
Floating through zero gravity with astronaut June.
皮纳特  拿起你的马克笔
Peanut, take your marker...
现在转动曲柄
Now turn the crank.
看呐  这能行  成功了
Look! It worked! It worked!
坐稳了  坐稳了
No, hold on! Hold on!
不
No.
弯曲吸管滑梯马上就完工了
Bendy Straw Slide is almost done.
看看你
Look at you.
过来  小可爱  我想和你谈几句
Come here, baby girl. I want to talk to you for a minute.
我知道你已经知道妈妈病了
I know you know Mommy's sick.
是啊
Yeah.
有几位特别的医生或许能帮我治病
There are some special doctors who might be able to help me.
但我去找他们治病就必须离开一阵子
But I have to go away for a while to see them.
你要离开多久
For how long are you going away?
这要看情况
Well, that just depends.
但是相信我  我会尽我所能好起来的
But believe me, I am gonna do everything I can to try and get better.
做个模范病人
Model patient.
我们会去探望你妈妈的  宝贝女儿
And we'll go visit, honey.
我知道这很吓人
Hey, I know this is scary,
但你要保持内心的微光永远闪亮
but you keep that little light in you shining bright.
我不知道自己能不能做到
I don't know if I can.
我相信你能做到
Well, I do.
因为你就是神奇乐园的奇迹
Because you are the wonder in Wonderland.
好了
Whew. Okay.
妈妈
Mom.
嗯  我会的
Yeah, I will.
你快回家了吗
Are you... Are you coming home soon?
好吧  我也爱你  妈妈
Okay. I love you, too, Mom.
保持内心的微光永远闪亮
Keep that little light in you shining bright.
你觉得皮纳特会在旋转木马上放什么动物
What kind of animal should Peanut put on that carousel?
你只需要把记号笔给皮纳特
All you have to do is give Peanut his marker,
然后悄悄告诉皮纳特
and whisper your wish into Peanut's ear.
我做不到
I can't.
-嘿  琼  -嘿  班基
- Oh, hey, June. - Hey, Banky.
我爸妈给我买了一套无人机装备
My parents got me this drone kit.
你可以帮忙把它组装起来
And we could use your help putting it together.
然后我们就可以把它用在神奇乐园里了
We could use it for Wonderland.
去吧  小琼琼  看起来很好玩
Go on, June Bug. That'll be fun.
这有没有经过FAA批准可在居民区使用
Is that FAA-certified for use in a residential area?
FAA: 美国联邦航空管理局
这玩意儿可极其危险
Those things can be insanely hazardous.
我们快无聊死了  可以说是无聊透顶
Well, we're insanely bored and, dare I say, desperate?
我们一直在山坡上滚着玩
We've stooped to repeatedly rolling each other down a hill for fun,
但我觉得拉杰快受不了了
and I don't think Raj can handle it anymore.
能来个人让世界别转了吗
Will someone please stop the world from spinning?
见到你很高兴  还是明天再说吧
Great seeing you. But maybe tomorrow.
但是我
But I... Oh.
抱歉了各位  今天没戏了
Sorry, guys. Not today.
我们能谈谈你怎么了吗
Can we talk about what's going on with you?
他们只想着玩神奇乐园
All they want to do is play with Wonderland.
你知道的
Well you know
爸爸  不行  不行
Dad. No! No, no, no.
别大惊小怪 这压根不是什么大事儿
Don't make this a thing. It's not a thing.
就算有事  也只是小事
Well, it is a thing, but the thing is, it's not a thing.
你说的明天  是指明天早上吗
When you say "tomorrow," you mean tomorrow morning?
反正是明天就对了
Just tomorrow!
来真的吗
Seriously?
-是下午  -没想到 吧
- Afternoon! - Surprise!
听说你想见见最喜欢的叔叔婶婶
Heard you wanted to see your favorite aunt and uncle.
然而他们却叫我们过来了
But they sent us instead.
这正是我跟她结婚的原因
Hey-O! That's why I married her!
过来让叔叔抱一个  小屁孩
Now bring it in for the good stuff, kiddo.
你真是一天一个样  都长这么大了
You're getting bigger every day. And so grown up.
长大了  也变漂亮了
Grown up and beautiful.
很高兴见到你们
It's good to see you,
虽然你们老是喜欢捏我的脸颊
even though you always do this to my cheeks.
这地方看起来真不错
Oh, the place looks great!
老天  你们是搬家过来的吗
Jeez. What, did you pack the whole house?
我还以为你们只是过来住两晚
I thought you guys were only coming for two nights.
只是一些必需品
Well, it's just the essentials.
我们买的是成套的东西
And anyway, we bought a set...
就想要把包装袋全用上
and we wanted to use all the bags.
-把礼物拿出来  -对了
- Oh, get the present. - Right.
我们把它放哪了
Now, where did we put it?
我们有礼物给你哦  是
We have a present for you, June. It's
一个摩天轮
a Ferris wheel!
我试着包装一下  但是
Uh... I tried wrapping it, but wrapping circular things
包装圆形的东西比我想象的难多了
is much harder than I would've imagined.
把它放到你的神奇乐园模型里一定很合适
I thought it would just be perfect for your Wonderland model.
你的神奇乐园呢
Where did all that go?
我们把那些东西都收起来了
We put Wonderland away.
那太可惜了
Well, that's a shame.
我昨天还和你妈妈说要帮你建造它
I told your mom yesterday we'd help you build it.
你的托尼叔叔在这方面可是行家
And I know your Uncle Tony!
我也喜欢玩具
I'm not above playing with toys.
我们把神奇乐园重建起来吧  小家伙
What do you say, tiny? Let's rebuild Wonderland.
我们不如聊点别的
Hey, hey why don't we talk about something else?
天气  纳税申报单  什么都行
Weather? Tax returns? Literally, anything else.
看看我找到了什么
Oh, look what I found.
什么
Wha...
神奇乐园的设计图
It's the blueprint for Wonderland.
我不玩神奇乐园了
I don't play with that anymore.
-但是  -请把它收起来吧
- But, sweetheart...   - Please, put that away.
-可是  -拜托了
- But...  - Just please!
你和你妈妈一起创造了这么美好的东西
This is a beautiful thing you and your mom did together, darling.
就像是真实存在的一样
To create something so real.
你可以
You can...
神奇乐园是假的  它不可能存在
Wonderland isn't real! It never could be real.
就算是真的我也绝对不会去那里
And even if it was, it's the last place in the world I'd want to visit!
不要
Oh, no.
琼琼
Oh, Junie.
-妈妈  -不  别去拿
- Mom!   - No, no, no wait!
对不起
I'm sorry.
孩子  等等
Sweetie, wait.
-琼琼  好消息  -什么
- Hey, Junie! Great news!  - Huh?
我有个好消息
I said great news!
我马上就好
I'll be done in a minute!
明天就要去数学夏令营了
Tomorrow is Math Camp!
我知道给干净的房子打扫卫生
And I know it's important to clean
是很重要的事
an already clean house...
你不如把精力用在整理行李上
but why don't you channel this nervous energy into packing?
这很危险
This is dangerous.
我不会去数学夏令营的
And I'm not going to Math Camp.
他们只会同情我
They're just gonna give me sad eyes.
-琼琼  -再说了  我在家也没闲着
- Junie...   - Besides, I got a lot to do around here.
你订的小麦草是三个月送一次
Is that a three-month or six-month renewal
还是半年送一次
on your wheatgrass deliveries?
-我填了半年一次  -我是想说
- I put in six.   - Uh, all I'm saying...
你的甘油三酯指数还是偏高
Your triglycerides are still on the high end.
对待身体可不能含糊
I'm not taking any chances with your health.
琼  你不能一直待在家里
June, you can't stay in here forever.
这个夏天我应该在家里照顾你
Look, I just know I need to be home this summer to take care of you.
没搞错吧  这个还有三天就过期了
Really? This expires in three days.
日期太接近了
You're cutting it way too close.
琼  今天我自己穿好衣服  做了早餐
June, today I got dressed and made breakfast all by myself
就和过去的41年一样
as I have been doing for the last 41 years.
八岁之前我还需要有人帮忙
The first seven I needed a little help,
但是现在我能自己解决
but since then I've been okay.
我不会去夏令营的
I am not going to Math Camp.
不要把牛油果和香蕉放在一起
Don't put the avocados next to the bananas.
放一起会熟的更快
They ripen too fast.
烤面包机调到三档温度就行了
And leave the toaster set to three.
边上烤焦了就不好吃了
You know you don't like it when the edges are too crispy.
我早上烤的面包不会有问题的
My morning toast will be fine.
冰箱里的牛奶可能会过期  检查一下
Oh, and the milk in the fridge could be out of date, so check it.
琼 琼 我自己能行
June, June, I'm gonna be okay.
我知道这对你来说是一大步
I know this is a big step.
你去了的话妈妈和我都会为你骄傲
Mom and I are both proud of you for going.
去算盘障碍赛大干一场吧
Now you get out there on Abacus Obstacle Course and skin a knee.
好
Okay.
你保证
Promise?
我保证
I promise.
-班基  -琼·贝利  我给你占了座
- Hey ya, Banky.  - Hey, June Bailey. Saved you a seat.
这绝对是我人生中最棒的夏天
This is gonna be the best summer ever!
再见
Oh. Goodbye!
嗨  同学们
Hey, campers!
大家都准备好去棒棒夏令营了吗
Okay, everybody here is heading to Camp Awe Sum, right?
如果没有  那你可上错车了
If you're not, you're on the rhom-bus.
我就喜欢她的几何学笑话
I love geometry humor.
我可以先讲讲我在棒棒夏令营
Now, I could start off with a million stories
发生的无数个故事
about my summers at Camp Awe Sum,
但我可不想转移话题
but I wouldn't want to go off on a tangent!
你们懂我的笑点吗
Are you getting my angle?
一  二  三  四
A-one, two... A-one, two-three, four.
我不该来夏令营的  我真糊涂
This is a terrible mistake. What was I thinking?
琼  我很好
June, I'm okay.
今天我自己穿好衣服还做了早餐
Today I got dressed and made breakfast all by myself.
天哪
Oh, no!
不能一整个暑假都让他独自在家
I can't leave him alone for an entire summer!
为什么钝角三角形...
Why is the obtuse triangle...
班基  我要你帮我  我要回家
Banky, I need your help. I need to get home.
什么  你爸爸会生气的
What? Your dad'll flip!
你会被禁足一辈子的
We're talking eternal groundation.
但他根本照顾不了自己
But he knows he can't function without me.
他说"想你"  简直就是求救
Look at this. "Miss you." It's like a cry for help!
不是吧  琼
Uh. I don't know, June.
我觉得你可能过度解读了
I think you might be reading a bit too much into this.
我顺着登山路线穿过森林
I'll take the hiking trails through the forest
午饭前就能到家
and be there before lunch.
这很容易
It's a no-brainer.
但我得先下车
But first I need to get off this bus.
你得帮我
And you have to help me.
求你了
Please!
-好吧  -太棒了
- Okay.  - Yes!
-班基我都想亲你了  -真的吗
- Banky, I could kiss you.  - Really?
-呃  不  -好吧
- Ew, no.  - Right.
我看看有什么用得上的
Now, what can I use?
好了
Okay.
你在学校演过戏对吧
You did the school play, right?
替补演员算吗
Does second understudy count?
差不多  你知道该怎么做
Uh, close enough. You know what to do.
天啊  我现在感觉不是很舒服
Oh, no! I don't think I'm feeling very well at this moment.
我觉得我要
I think I might...
我要忍不住了
I don't think I can hold it down!
忍不住了
I can't hold it no more!
天啊  我要吐了
Oh, no! It's here!
要吐了
It's here!
你吐得太恶心了
Ugh, you chucked a yuck!
停车
Stop the bus!
好了  不准随便乱走
Okay, nobody wander off!
小心有蛇
And watch out for snakes.
它们到处都是
They're everywhere.
蛇
Snakes?
琼  琼  琼
June? June? June?
做得好  班基
Nice one, Banky.
你吐的超恶心的
You chucked a yuck!
有一次我吃了玉米热狗后生病了
I got sick from a corndog once.
我整个人从内到外都疼
It hurt all the way inside of my bones.
我妈说是因为那热狗已经放了两周
My mom said it was because it was two weeks old.
但我用微波炉加热后就超级好吃的
But I put it in the microwave and it was delicious.
我的天啊
Holy hypotenuse!
对  肯定是因为吃了玉米热狗
Oh, yeah, definitely the corndog.
好了  你是心悸发作了吗
Okay, are you having heart palpitations?
等一下  这个为什么会在这
Wait. Why is this here?
你  给我回来
Hey, get back here!
痛
Ow.
抓住你了
Gotcha!
这是
Is this...
不会吧
No way.
这怎么可能
How is this possible?
有人吗
Hello!
你是
Are you...
皮纳特
Peanut.
我这是在
I'm in...
神奇乐园
Wonderland.
风暴云
Storm clouds?
神奇乐园里不应该有风暴云的
There shouldn't be storm clouds in Wonderland.
布莫  我们跟不上了
Boomer! We can't keep up!
是欢迎熊布莫吗
Boomer the Welcome Bear?
他也在这吗
He's here, too?
快逃命吧
Run for your life!
带上她  快跑  小个子
Grab her! Get moving, pipsqueak!
这是怎么回事
What's going on?
我们为什么要追布莫
Why are we chasing Boomer?
我们没有追他
Oh, we're not chasing him.
是他们在追我们
They're chasing us!
去火箭路集合
Regroup at Rocket Road!
逃到安全的地方呀  小短腿快逃呀
Skipping to safety, skipping to safety! Tra-la-la-la!
-格斯  去放下篷子  -好
- Gus, gnaw that awning down.  - I'm on it.
库珀  去启动泵
Cooper, start the pump.
史蒂夫
Steve...
我来起草逃离计划
I'll draft up an exit plan.
你去做诱饵
you're the bait.
当然是我了  诱饵走咯
Of course I am. Baiting away.
布莫  你要拿命来保护她
Boomer, you protect her with your life. Hey!
嘿  布莫 这里发生了什么
Hey, Boomer. What is going on around here?
这看起来像什么  我们在打仗啊
What does it look like? We're at war!
打战  神奇乐园中是没有战争的
War? There's no fighting in Wonderland.
待着别动
Stay put.
如果被他们发现  他们会
Because if they see us, they will...
自己救自己吧
Save yourself!
他们就会怎样
They'll what?
布莫  别说一半啊
Boomer, finish the sentence.
他们就会怎样
They'll what?
为什么他们在破坏乐园
Why are they destroying the park?
各位  你们好呀
Hey, you guys!
我在这里呀
Over here!
放马过来吧
Dinner is served.
神奇乐园  麻烦出现
Wonderland, we have a problem.
史蒂夫  等一下
Steve, hold it.
哦上天啊
Uh... Oh, dear.
-坚持住  -我在坚持
- Hold it.  - I am holding it.
我真的在坚持啊
I'm literally holding it.
-坚持住  -天啊
- Hold it.  - Ahhh!
不我不行了  我不干了我要溜了
Oh, no, I've dropped it! I've dropped it and I left it!
我要离开这里
Uh, I'm out of here.
格斯  库珀  给火箭泵油
Gus, Cooper, pump the rocket!
我们要开始啦
We got to boom-shaka-boom!
一二一二一二一二
Boom-shaka-boom! Boom-shaka-boom!
锁定装载  倒数了伙计们
Locked and loaded. Countdown, guys!
四  三
Four... Three...
逃到安全的地方去呀  逃呀
Skipping to safety! Skipping to safety!
我快要逃离危险啦
I'm almost out of danger!
继续打泵  伙计们
Keep pumping, guys!
一二一二一二一二
Boom-shaka-boom! Boom-shaka-boom!
真可爱  但是太闹心了
So cute! But so naughty.
系好安全带吧
Now buckle up,
僵尸猩猩们
Chimpanzombies.
一
one!
我就是世界顶级的诱饵
World-class bait.
这不是真的  我这是在做梦
This isn't really happening. I'm... I'm having a fever dream.
啊我这里很敏感的
Ah, I'm sensitive there!
快看那里  你看
Hey! Ow! Hey!
去搜查一下  那个背包
Check it. Backpack!
嘻嘻  我闻到零食的味道
Ooh, ooh, I smell treats!
我的  我先说的
Dibs! I call dibs!
嘿  那是我的  还给我
Hey! That's mine! Give it back! Whoo!
耶宝贝  击掌  击两次
Boom, baby. Foot five! Foot ten! Oh, yeah!
你丫的  你个混蛋
You son of a woodchip. Ow! Splinterface.
我就只是来看一下  可以吧
Let's have a little lookie-loo, shall we?
自我提醒一下
With a self-reminder
这完全是侵犯别人隐私的行为
that this is an utter invasion of another's privacy.
等一下  小可爱
Hold the roll, cutie-pie.
啊  我投降
Ahhh! I surrender!
脚下有锋利的物体  安全员已到现场
Sharp objects underfoot. Safety Officer onsite.
你刚才是叫我小甜心吗  啊
Did you just call me cutie-pie? Ahhh!
僵尸猩猩把她抓了  是不是
The Chimpanzombies got her, didn't they?
都是我的错
It's all my doing.
都怪我有迟发性冬眠障碍
All thanks to a late-onset hibernation disorder.
没事的  他们没有抓住我
Uh, it's okay. They didn't get me.
哦  谢天谢地  否则我永远都
Oh, thank heavens! I couldn't have lived with my...
等等  布莫从不睡觉
Wait, Boomer never sleeps.
嘿  小心点
Hey, watch it!
你们这是怎么了  你们看起来很
What happened to you guys? You're so...
我觉得你想说的是可悲
I think the word you're looking for is "pathetic."
-我可没这么说  -你没必要说
- I didn't say that. - Ugh, you didn't have to.
你有名字吗  酷女孩
So, you got a name, haircut?
-我是琼  -你好  琼
- I am June. - Hello, June.
-我叫  -史蒂夫  我知道你是谁
- My name is... - Steve. I know who you are.
你认识我们吗
You know who we are?
我觉得不会有人记得我们  疼
I didn't think anybody still remembered. Ow!
你们是神奇乐园里的奇迹
You guys are the wonder in Wonderland.
起码曾经是
Or at least you were.
这里发生了什么
What happened to this place?
黑暗来袭
The Darkness happened.
它是在齿轮秋千变慢的时候出现的
It came when Clockwork Swings began to slow.
还带来了
And brought with it...
好吧  把手放下来  甘道夫
All right, bring it down, Gandalf.
哦  好的
Oh, right.
好了  我们继续
Okay, here we go.
那天和往常一样
It was a day just like any other here in Wonderland
但奇怪的事情发生了
when the strangest thing happened.
齿轮秋千  也就是乐园的核心
Clockwork Swings, the heart of the park,
完全停止了运作
came to a dead stop.
那是我们第一次见到它  黑暗.
And that's when we first saw it. The Darkness.
随之而来的邪恶物质
It brought an evil
把神奇猩猩玩偶
that transformed the WonderChimp dolls
变成了一群僵尸猩猩
into an army of Chimpanzombies.
从那以后僵尸猩猩每天都在打仗
Every day since, the Chimpanzombies have waged war,
他们把乐园拆成碎片一块块喂给黑暗
tearing apart the park and feeding it piece by piece into the Darkness,
乐园彻底消失了
never to be seen again.
你们没有办法吗
There was nothing you could do?
连皮纳特也束手无策吗
Not even Peanut?
皮纳特在哪
Where is Peanut?
他冒险独自离开
He ventured out on his own to try
想要亲自重启齿轮秋千
and restart Clockwork Swings by hand.
为什么他不施魔法
Then why didn't he use his magic?
他只说重启齿轮秋千
He just said that he knew restarting Clockwork Swings
是让神奇乐园起死回生的唯一方法
was the only way to bring the life back into Wonderland.
但是
But...
我们失去了重启齿轮秋千的希望
And we lost any hope of turning Clockwork Swings back on,
再也见不到乐园恢复往日荣光的那天了
and one day restoring the park to all its former glory.
-齿轮秋千  -你拿着的是什么
- Clockwork Swings. - What you got?
这是  乐园的设计图吗
It's a blueprint... Of the park?
像是墨菲特小姐把她的名字涂鸦在上面
Seems like Little Miss Muffet graffitied her name on it.
这不是涂鸦
It's not graffiti.
你怎么会有神奇乐园的设计图
How do you have a blueprint of Wonderland?
我小时候和我妈妈创造了神奇乐园
My mom and I invented Wonderland when I was little,
不知怎的  它变成真的了
and somehow it came to life.
这真是最
That's got to be the most...
棒的消息了
Splendiferous news ever!
你为什么不去睡觉呢  布莫
Why don't you just go back to sleep, Boomer?
不  我相信她的眼神
No, I believe it in her eyes.
因为如果她真是神奇乐园的建造者
Because if she really is the creator of Wonderland,
那她一定可以修好齿轮秋千
she can fix Clockwork Swings.
额
Well...
等等  这不是我们讨论的重点吧
Well, that is not where I thought this discourse was heading.
我还以为你是一个
I was imagining that you were a...
蜜蜂
Honeybee!
我不是蜜蜂
Huh? I'm not a honeybee.
-兔子  -什么
- Rabbit! - Huh?
史蒂夫  别让我们丢脸
Steve, you're embarrassing the team.
死亡
Death!
我现在很疑惑什么是死亡兔子
I am so confused right now about what a Death Rabbit is.
布莫  去保护安全屋  大家分散跑
Boomer, go secure the safe house. Guys, scatter!
两人一组  我要葛蕾塔
Buddy system! I call Greta!
算了算了  我要琼
Never mind! I call June!
-我们必须离开这里  -说得好
- We got to get out of here. - Good plan.
-快想  快想  -数到五我们就跑
- Think, June. Think, think, think. - We go in five.
-那行不通  -收到  我数到三了
- That could never work. - Roger that. We run in three.
那不可能行的通
That couldn't possibly work.
然后我们跳  竭尽全力去跳
Then we skip. Skip like there's no tomorrow.
欢迎来到神奇乐园
Welcome to Wonderland.
跳到安全的地方  跳  啊
Skipping to safety. Skipping... Ahhh! Tra-la-la-la.
你太棒啦  太太太棒啦
You're splendiferous! Splen-diddy-doo!
啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦
Tra-la-la-la-la-la-la-la...
跳  跳到安全的地方
Skipping to, skipping to safety.
动起来  快动起来  推动鱼鳍的时候
Please work, please work. When you push the fin,
飞鱼就会复活
the fish'll come to life!
小心  它在你身后
Look out! It's right behind you!
你想停下来吃点冰淇淋吗
Would you like to stop for an ice cream?
不  去出口  去出口
No! Exit, exit, exit!
随时都要将手和腿放在车内
Keep your arms and legs inside the ride at all times!
今天就别想了  僵尸猩猩
Not today, Chimpanzombies!
回见啦
See you later.
好的  很快回去
Okay. Come back soon.
我怎么回来了
How did I get back here?
你太棒啦
You're splendiferous!
太太太棒啦
Splen-diddy-doo!
坏僵尸猩猩  坏僵尸猩猩
Bad Chimpanzombies! Bad Chimpanzombies!
我来了  琼
I got you, June!
神奇乐园的每一天都无比奇妙
Every day is a wonderful day in Wonderland!
哦  我的尾巴
Oh, my tail.
快点  快点
Come on, hurry!
格斯  库珀  检查北侧西侧的电线
Gus, Cooper, check the north and west perimeter wires.
史蒂夫  上瞭望台确保我们没有被跟踪
Steve, get to lookout and make sure we weren't followed.
收到
Roger that.
你还活着
You're alive!
我好担心  都不知道该怎么办
Oh, I was so worried, I didn't know what to do.
我都开始烤棉花糖披萨饺了
I started baking marshmallow calzones.
我们失去了欢乐世界  布莫
We lost Happy Happy Land, Boomer.
是吗  天哪
We did? Oh, my.
乐园已经被毁了大半
That's over half the park gone now.
如果失去另一半要怎么办
What happens if we lose the other half?
是啊  我们该怎么办
Yeah. What's gonna happen to us?
我不知道
I don't know.
-但至少我们还有披萨饺  -还有她
But at least we got calzones! And her.
她  情况不对的时候她只知道往出口跑
Her? When the going got tough, she ran for the exits.
我得回家找我爸爸
I need to get home to my dad.
而且如果真是她创造了神奇乐园
And if she really did create Wonderland,
鬼知道是什么意思
whatever that means,
她就会知道那些出口已经不存在了
she would know that those exits aren't even exits anymore!
但是我和妈妈创建乐园时它们还在的
Well, they were exits when my mom and I created the park.
很抱歉  整个地方都乱套时我不在这里
Sorry I wasn't around when this whole place went haywire,
而且标记为"出口"的出口也出不去了
and it became impossible to exit from an exit marked "exit."
你们知道吗  "出口"这个动词
Did you know the verb "exit"
源于拉丁动词"exeoexitum"
comes from the Latin verb exeoexitum
而这个词又派生于希腊语动词
which derives from the Greek verb
"eximexite"
eximeexite?
看来我打扰了
Seems I have backed
你们的谈话
into the middle of something here.
退出群聊  哔  哔  哔
Backing out! Beep, beep, beep...
哔
Beep.
好了  我们知道打开出口的唯一方法
Okay, so we know the only way to open the exits
就是使乐园恢复运转
is to get the park back up and running.
而让齿轮秋千重新转起来是关键
Turning on Clockwork Swings is the key to that.
别让女孩抱太大希望  布莫
Oh, don't get the girl's hopes up, Boomer.
没办法再运作起来了
There's no way to turn it back on.
我们去看过很多次了
Yeah, we've been there a bunch of times.
各个方面都检查了
Looked at it every which way.
是我全方位检查
I looked at it every which way,
他只是坐在那里吃木片薯片
he just sat there eating woodchips.
-我那时候饿了  -他就坐在那里
- I was hungry! - He just sat there...
-还困了  -在我全面检查的时候
- And sleepy. - while I looked at it every which way.
但她还没看过
But she hasn't.
如果她创造了它  她就能修好它
And if she created it, she can fix it. Uh...
所以神奇乐园只是你想象虚构出来的吗
So Wonderland is just a figment of your imagination?
可以这样说吧
Something like that.
让我猜猜
And, uh, let me guess.
也就是说我们都是你幻想出来的
That means we're all figments of your imagination.
也不能完全说是
I wouldn't put it exactly like...
哦  存在主义危机
Oh, an existential crisis!
我就知道今天还缺了些什么
I knew this day was missing something.
那你也能想象到要我们转动脑筋
Well, you can imagine this may be a little hard
可能会有点困难
for us to wrap our heads around.
也许你可以给我一些证据
Perhaps you will indulge me with some proof?
好吧
Fine.
每天早上史蒂夫都会喝早茶
Every morning, Steve drinks his morning tea,
2.6克伯爵茶
2.6 grams of loose Earl Grey
倒入250毫升86.1度的开水
to 250 milliliters of 86.1 degree water
浸泡3分11秒
steeped for three minutes and 11 seconds
再加上一点杏仁奶来完美点缀
and garnished to perfection with a spot of almond milk.
看吧  琼万岁
See? All hail June!
好吧  先别高兴得太早
Yeah, let's not get carried away.
不过或许我能修好齿轮秋千
But I may be able to fix Clockwork Swings.
-皮纳特本来是我们的纽带  -纽带
- Peanut was the glue around here. - The glue?
纽带  他让我们大家聚在了一起
The glue. He kept us all together.
看  大伙们都经历了太多
Look, these guys have suffered a lot already.
我愿意听从你的指挥
And I'm willing to follow your lead here,
因为我实在没有办法了
because I'm running out of options.
但你必须向我保证真的还有机会
But you've got to promise me there's a real shot at this.
所以请告诉我  我们的指望不会落空
So tell me that you're not serving up false hope.
我很擅长修理东西
Well, I was pretty good at fixing things.
但你得带我到齿轮秋千那里去
But you got to get me to Clockwork Swings.
哇  大奇迹
Wow, The Grand Wonder.
比我想象的还要大
It's even bigger than I thought.
别慢吞吞的  钟表秋千就在前面
Come on, slowpokes. The Clocks are just up ahead.
你是怎么做到的  琼
Oh, how did you do it, June? Huh?
能创造出这么一个不在人间行走的女子
To create such a woman who doesn't walk through this world.
她是用滑的
She glides!
那丝滑的红发  那勾人的獠牙
That silken red hair. Those come-hither tusks.
-葛蕾塔  -你想干什么
- Greta? - Oh, what do you want?
不  没什么  点名而已
What? No, nothing here. Just a bit of a roll call.
史蒂夫  到
"Steve!" "Present and accounted for."
点名结束
Roll call complete.
哦  天哪
Oh, boy.
这比我们做的模型还要复杂一点
This is a little more complicated than the model we made.
看起来液压系统是密封的
The hydraulics seem to be sealed and stuff.
没有泄漏什么的  嗯
No leaks or anything, um...
肯定是某个齿轮卡住了
It must be that one of the gears is jammed.
找到了  她正在修理
Eureka! She's fixing it.
我们在见证一个奇迹
We're witnessing a miracle.
更像是在诊断  说不上是奇迹
More of a diagnosis and certainly not a miracle,
但这确实是比以往还要好的解决方案
but it does bring us closer to a solution than we've ever been before.
如果你是想发表意见
If you're trying to make a statement,
那就来吧  大块头
have at me, big guy.
必须让这个设备运行起来
Got to get this ride started.
我知道你有答案  请告诉我答案
I know you have the answer. Please tell me the answer!
-上面写了什么  -我看不见
- Well, what does it say? - I can't see!
被我的名字挡住了
My name's covering it.
什么鬼啊  太不优秀了
What the chuck? Unsplendiferous.
不用担心  实施B计划
Not to worry! Plan B it is.
那到底是什么呢
Which is what, exactly?
妈妈  为什么你要写在这上面
Mom, why did you write on this?
以前上面有什么
What used to be there?
我不知道  但我得搞清楚
I don't know. I got to figure this out.
别跟我说这种话  琼
Don't do this to me, June.
这不是你的设计图吗
It's your blueprint, isn't it?
是啊  但我已经好久
Yeah. But it's been a while since I...
如果是多项选择题  我能多答对几个
If the test were multiple choice, I'd do much better.
躲开找掩护  躲开找掩护
Duck and cover! Duck and cover!
嘿  快回来
Hey, get back here! Whoa!
-我抓到了  -不  是我抓到了
- I got it!  - No, I got it.
我们需要那块设计图
We need that blueprint!
库珀  快抓住它
Get it, Coop!
这一点都不好玩  布莫  天哪…
This is not fun. Boomer, for goodness...
不  别过去  烟花瀑布是死亡陷阱
No! No, stop! Fireworks Falls is a death trap!
滚开
Get off.
我说停下
Stand down, I say!
必须把它拿回来  那个不能丢
We have to get it! We can't lose it.
把我扔过去  我去拿
Throw me! I'll get it!
不  扔我过去
No, throw me!
-不  这是我的主意  -哦天哪
- No, it was my idea! - Oh, gosh.
我抓到了  是我的  你戳我眼睛了
I got it, I got it! Mine! You poked me in the eye!
都怪你  为什么总是怪我
Your fault. Why is it always my fault?
你们玩我呢吧
You've got to be kidding me!
够了
Enough!
我命令你们离开这个平台
I command you to remove yourself from this platform!
我受够了你们这几个月来一直胡闹
I have been putting up with this reckless abandon for months on end,
我的灵魂受到了侵蚀
and it is chipping away at my soul.
我太累了…
I'm so very tired...
那是什么声音
What is that sound?
哦  不
Oh, no.
哦  我的老天鹅
Oh, deary me.
不要慌  我们到高地去
Okay, fear not. We simply must reach higher ground.
高处都是一心想让我们死的密探
Ahhh! Which is teeming with agent provocateurs bent on our demise!
停  前往神奇乐园
Stop, drop and roll to Wonderland!
点火  点火  点火  点火  点火
Fire! Fire! Fire! Fire! Fire! Fire! Fire!
快跑
Run!
大家各自逃命去
Every man for himself!
-用你背上的刺  史蒂夫  -有道理
- Use your quills, Steve! - Quite right.
没错  我就知道
Yeah, of course.
大家还好吗
Everyone okay?
等等  琼呢
Wait, where's June?
-呃  在那儿  -哦不
- Uh, there. - Oh, no.
坚持住  琼  你会没事的
Hold on, June! You'll be okay!
你说起来容易
Easy for you to say.
救命
Help!
谢谢  布莫
Thanks, Boomer!
-你做到了  -干得漂亮
- You did it! - Well done!
我在桥上与你们会和
Meet me at the bridge!
也许不会
Or not.
不用再这么做了
Don't need to do that again.
零重力空间
Zero-G Land.
皮纳特
Peanut?
哦  天哪  嘿  皮纳特
Oh, my gosh! Hey, Peanut!
你在哪
Where did you...
-你在做什么  -我就知道你还活着
- What are you doing? - You're alive! I knew it!
-你是谁  -葛蕾塔和布莫的朋友
- Who are you? - A friend of Greta and Boomer.
事实上  每个人的朋友
Actually, everyone.
他们肯定很高兴  我们去找他们吧
They're gonna be so happy. Let's go find them!
不  不  不
No, no, no, no.
快走吧  我在烟花瀑布和他们走丢了
Come on, I lost them at Fireworks Falls.
皮纳特  你怎么了
Peanut, what happened to you?
什么我怎么了  僵尸猩猩把我抓走了
What do you mean, what happened to me? The Chimpanzombies had me.
然后我逃了出来  跑到了这里
I was able to escape, and I made it up here.
-然后现在你  -现在我在整理糖果
- And now you're... - And now I'm sorting the candy.
我刚到的时候这儿真是一团糟
It was a mess when I got here.
相信我
Believe me.
我必须把蓝的归到一起
I had to put the blues with the blues,
把绿的归到一起
and the greens with the greens...
如果你害怕乐园
If you're scared of the park...
我不害怕乐园  我只是
I'm not scared of the park. It's just...
这里很安全
It's safe in here.
-但你一个人  -在这里我很安全
- But you're alone. - Where nothing can hurt me.
好吧  但你总不能一辈子呆在这里
Well, you can't stay in here forever.
谁说不行
Says who?
这种事又没有规定
There's no rules for something like this.
我知道这怎么用  你只要挥动马克笔
I know how this works. You just wave your marker.
我也希望它还能用
I wish it still worked that way.
但你是了不起的皮纳特
But you're Peanut the Splendiferous.
了不起  对  以前是
Splendiferous. Yeah, I used to be.
神奇乐园的一切都是你创造的啊
All these amazing things in Wonderland came from you.
那都是假的
That is a lie.
我只是个传声筒
I was just the middleman.
所有的想法  灵感  都来自
All the ideas, the inspiration, it came from...
在你耳边低语的声音
A voice whispering in your ear.
女人的声音
A woman's voice.
你怎么知道的  我从未告诉过任何人
How do you know about that? I never told anyone.
那不重要
It doesn't matter.
而不久前
And not too long ago...
她的声音就
The sound of her voice, it just...
消失了
went away.
然后黑暗开始了
And then the Darkness took over.
我猜不管她是谁  她都把我忘了
I guess whoever she was, she forgot about me.
可我一直在等
I kept waiting.
我一直希望她能够回来
I kept hoping she would come back
助我对抗黑暗
to help me fight against the Darkness,
但我感到太
but I just felt so...
孤单了
Alone.
皮纳特  有件事我要告诉你
Peanut, there's something I need to tell...
-别嘘我  这很重要  -我们得走了
- Don't shush me. This is important. - We have to go!
他们找到我们了
They found us.
他们一定是跟着你来的
They must have followed you in.
我们得走了  立刻
We need to move now!
你的记号笔
Your marker!
-别管了  那笔没用了  -不是的
- Leave it. It's worthless! - No, it's not.
当心
Look out!
-天啊  -坚持住
- Oh, my gosh. - Hold on!
不
Oh, no!
抓住你啦
Gotcha!
没有出口
There's no way out.
你走那边
There is for you.
琼  快走
June, go!
有人吗
Guys?
有人吗  布莫  葛蕾塔
Guys? Boomer? Greta?
琼  你在哪
June! Where are you?
我在这
Over here!
我们到处找你
We've been looking all over for you.
-我找到皮纳特了  -什么
- I found Peanut. - What?
他躲在零重力区  他还活着
He was hiding in Zero-G Land. He's alive.
-皮纳特还活着啊  -太棒了
Peanut's alive? How brilliant!
但他被僵尸猩猩抓走了
But he was taken by the Chimpanzombies.
他们把他抓去黑暗里了
They're carrying him to the Darkness!
那我们去找他吧
Then let's go get him!
但是我们要先把桥修好
But we need to rebuild that bridge.
我们可以用旋转木马的支撑柱建桥
We could use the support posts of the old carousel.
那些柱子太不结实了
They're too rickety.
这点子很好  还有什么能用的
But it's the right idea. What else can we use?
要快点想
Got to think fast.
万一皮纳特有什么三长两短
If something bad were to happen to Peanut,
我不能原谅我自己
I couldn't live with myself.
等等  你说什么
Wait, wait, wait. What do you mean?
都是我的错
It's all my fault.
你做错什么了
What's all your fault?
黑暗
The Darkness.
我想可能是我创造出来的
I think maybe I did create it.
我不是故意的  但应该就是我干的
I didn't mean to! But I think I did it.
你是说你创造了黑暗吗
You created the Darkness?
我不明白
I don't understand.
如果你建造了神奇乐园
If you created Wonderland,
为什么还要摧毁它呢
why would you want to destroy it?
我不是故意的  我那时很害怕
It wasn't on purpose. I was afraid.
结果黑暗占据了上风
The Darkness took over.
我试过  只是我不再关心乐园了
I tried, but I just stopped caring about the park.
不过没关系  我们还可以挽回
Anyway, it doesn't matter. We can fix it.
用这个
With this!
只要我们能找到穿越山谷的路
If we can find a way to cross that ravine,
让这东西回到皮纳特手里
and put it back in Peanut's hands,
我们就能让钟表秋千动起来
we can get Clockwork Swings up and running.
相信我  我们可以
Trust me. We can...
相信你  我们一直都相信你
Trust you? We've been trusting you!
如果我们知道你是罪魁祸首
But if we knew you were the person responsible for all this?
我们绝不会错信你
I never would've let us make that mistake.
走吧各位  天黑了
Come on, guys, it's dark.
我们自己解决这个烂摊子
We'll figure this out on our own.
为什么  为什么你不在意了
Why would you stop... Why would you stop caring?
我们做错了什么
What did we do wrong?
你们什么也没做错  你们都很棒
You guys didn't do anything wrong. You guys are amazing.
可是你创造了黑暗
You created the Darkness.
布莫
Boomer.
对不起  妈妈
I'm sorry, Mom.
你就是神奇乐园的奇迹
You are the wonder in Wonderland.
必须找到穿越的路
Got to find a way across.
欢迎来到伟大奇迹
Welcome to the Grand Wonder!
抱歉  布莫
Oops. Sorry, Boomer.
欢迎来到伟大奇迹
Welcome to the Grand Wonder!
什么可以用得到呢
Now, what can I use?
有了
Ah. Got it.
点火启动啦
We have ignitialization!
不给邻居搞破坏
"Without wrecking the neighborhood."
我跟你讲  肯定没有办法重建那座桥
I'm telling you, I don't see any way to rebuild that bridge.
你这种心态肯定找不到办法
Yeah, well, not with that attitude.
或许你们想来看看这个
Um, you may want to come and see this.
听起来像是空中战机攻击
Sounds like another SkyFlinger attack.
低调行事  待在后面
Stay low. Stay back.
我会是皮纳特  天啊
Dang! Well, I'll be Peanut...oh!
那是  那是琼
Is that... It's June!
她做到了
She did it.
她真的做到了
She's actually done it.
你看到了吗
Would you look at that?
这是怎么回事
So what's all this about?
是时候让神奇乐园重生了
It's time to bring Wonderland back to life.
你说什么
Huh? What?
我知道我让你们失望了
I know I let you down.
但我想让它回归正轨
But I want to make it right.
你怎么知道这有用
How do you know it'll work?
因为是我建造了这个地方
Because I built this place.
我妈妈和我一起
My mom and I did.
但她病了  我们不得不停下来
But she got sick and had to stop.
我又很害怕
And I got scared.
我太怕失去她  以至于迷失了自我
So scared of losing her that I lost myself.
她不会喜欢我变成这个样子
And she would hate to see how I changed.
也不会喜欢我们大家变成这个样子
How we've all changed.
那现在就准备就绪吧
Now, buckle up!
我们要像风一样坐那个过山车
We're gonna ride that coaster like the wind.
谁跟我一起
Who's with me?
-我跟你一起 琼  -我们都是
- I'm with you, June. - We are all with you.
对 没错
Yeah, that's right.
疼啊
Ow!
我依然相信你
I still believe in you.
我更像是那种两脚站地的类型
I'm more of a "two feet on the ground" kinda guy.
那个过山车应该是有重量限制的吧
I think there's a weight restriction on that ride, isn't there?
得了吧  布莫
Oh, come on, Boomer.
绝对没门儿
There is absolutely no way...
噢 不要
Oh, no.
我决不
I will ev...
呃 我们搞定
Uh, we got this.
吃太多棉花糖披萨饺了
Too many marshmallow calzones.
朋友们 我又做那个奇怪的绑架梦了
Hey, guys. I had that weird kidnapping dream again.
我想知道那个梦是啥意思
I wonder what it means.
布莫 我们马上上去
Boomer! We'll be right up!
葛蕾塔去取另一辆车了
Greta just has to get the other cart!
我想下去
I want to be down.
-只有一个办法  -像小鸟一样飞下来
- Only one way down!  - Yeah, fly like a bird, bro.
但我不是小鸟 鸟的嘴巴超可怕的
But I'm not a bird! Birds are terrifying, with those beaks,
还有他们的爪子
and those talons,
还有甲型流感
and influenza type A!
快点呀  葛蕾塔
Come on, Greta.
你们确定抵住轮子了对吧
You guys did block the wheels, right?
-原来这个是这么用的啊  -完了
- Oh, that's what this is for! - Oops.
各位
Ugh. Guys!
这是什么几率的巧合
Huh. What are the odds?
非常非常小的几率
Astronomically small.
不不不不  不要啊
No, no, no. No!
很好
Oh, terrific.
天啊  他在盯着我看
Uh... Oh, gosh, he's looking at me.
哦不不不
Oh, no, no.
走开  走开
Shoo, shoo.
快走开
Get out of here.
乖乖鸟儿  嘿  你朋友们来啦
Nice birdie. Oh, hey! I hear your friends!
求求你别动
Please don't move.
你没听
You're not lis...
哦不  不  不  不
Oh, no. No, no, no.
你应该等着的
You were supposed to wait!
他走反了 如果不给布莫掉头
He's going the wrong way! If we don't turn Boomer around...
他会被炸成一个葱油饼
He'll be fried like a funnel cake!
格斯  库珀  把上轨道降到下轨道
Gus, Cooper! Drop the upper track to the lower one,
然后我们把布莫引到安全的滑道上
and we'll reroute Boomer to safety.
收到
On it!
我们需要一些结实的绳子
We'll need some kind of rope,
要那些能够拉得住他的
something strong to stop him with.
明白
Got it.
快把我弄下去
Get me off of this thing!
我们做不到了
We're not gonna make it!
-哦老弟  -起码我们吃了顿晚饭
- Oh, man. - At least we got dinner.
糟了
Oh, no!
-甘草糖吗  -我们只找到了这个
- Licorice? - That's what we got.
行  史蒂夫 把它发射给布莫
Ok. Steve, fire this to Boomer
我们用这个拉住他
and we'll use it to slow him down.
收到
Roger that.
布莫 抓住绳子
Boomer! Catch the rope!
好的
Okay!
射程400米  风力3节  西南风
Range, 400 meters. Winds, three knots southwest.
预备
Ready...
救命  救命  救命
Help, help, help!
瞄准
aim...
发射
fire!
疯了
Nuts.
-好吧  那个没起作用  -你说呢
- Well, that didn't work. - Ya think?
快让它停下来啊
Make it stop!
等等  我们还是能穿过去的
Wait, we could all still get across.
大家拉紧绳子
Okay, everybody, pull tight!
继续拉
Keep pulling.
这对我们来说是个非常可怕的转折点
This is beginning to feel like a terrible turn of events for us all.
我跟他一起
I'm with him.
冲击准备
Brace for impact!
我可以醒来了 醒来吧
I'm ready to wake up now, ready to wake up.
布莫 你本来就醒着
You are awake, Boomer.
我醒着吗 我醒着呢 我们做到了
I'm awake? I mean, I'm awake! We did it.
-你做到了  -我做到了  做到了吗
- You did it. - I did it. I mean...I did it?
-你是个男子汉  -你是个男子汉熊
- You da man! - You're the man-bear!
我是男子汉
I'm the man!
你是男子汉
You're the man,
而我们只是动物王国中能够开口讲话的
and we are just the various members of the animal kingdom with the
几种动物恰好挂在了男子汉旁边
power of speech hanging next to the man.
没错
Yes, you are.
你太棒啦
You're splendiferous!
去他的芝士小饼干
Holy cheesy chips!
哇塞
Oh, crikey!
皮纳特
Peanut.
我们来晚了
We're too late.
天啊 我们现在该怎么办
Oh, gosh. What do we do now?
-不是我们  -孩子  你有什么主意
- Not "we." - What do you have in mind, kid?
现在是我该去做点什么了
It's about what I need to do.
我要去黑暗中把皮纳特带回来
I need to go into the Darkness and bring Peanut back.
-什么  不行  -她啥意思
- What? No! - What's she talking about?
琼
June...
它太强大了 没有人能活着出来
It's too powerful. Nothing ever comes out.
我可以  葛蕾塔
I got this, Greta.
我是神奇乐园的奇迹
I am the wonder in Wonderland.
I am the wonder in Wonderland!
皮纳特  你在哪
Peanut? Where are you?
琼  是你吗
June? Is that you?
皮纳特  坚持住
Peanut! Hold on!
琼
June?
皮纳特
Peanut!
你没事吧  受伤了吗
Are you okay? Are you hurt?
我很难过他们也把你抓到这里
I'm so sorry they got you, too.
你得想办法把我们弄出去
You've got to get us out of here.
我也想啊
I wish I could.
但是我都说了  我的灵感离我而去
But I told you, my inspiration, she left me.
她再也没回来过
She's never coming back.
你不知道  她正在努力回到我们身边
You don't know that. She's out there, trying to get back to us.
-我们  -对
- Us? - Yeah.
她就是我妈妈  我最了解她的就是
She's my mom, and if there's one thing I know,
她决不放弃
it's that she is not giving up.
所以我们也决不放弃
So neither should we.
没有她的话
Without her,
我什么也不能创造
I'll never create again.
你能
Yes, you will.
不要向恐惧低头
Don't give in to the fear.
你内心的光比黑暗更强大
Your light is stronger than the Darkness.
-拿着  -但是没有她的话
- Now take this. - But without her...
你不用再担心了
You don't have to worry about that anymore.
什么意思
What do you mean?
因为
Because...
我在这
I'm here.
皮纳特  用弯曲吸管做一个
Peanut, build us the biggest slide in the whole wide world
全世界最大的滑梯
and make it out of bendy straws.
好让我们离开这里
Now let's get out of here.
弯曲吸管
Bendy straws, hmm?
听起来是一个无与伦比的主意
That sounds like a splendiferous idea!
马上就做
Coming right up.
快点  再做一个
Quick, make another one!
去齿轮秋千
To Clockwork Swings!
看
Look.
她成功了  他们成功了
She's doing it! They made it!
拍拍尾巴  哦吼
Well, slap my tail. Tally ho!
天啊
Oh, dear.
我们得去帮他们
We've got to help them.
这就去  坐稳了  琼
That we do. Hang on, June!
太棒了
Well done!
我觉得我欠你们一个说法
Guess I owe you guys an explanation, huh?
我们很高兴你还活着
We're just happy you're alive.
既然你回来了  那就开始修那些齿轮
And since you are, how about you get those clocks started
让我们的乐园重获生机吧
and bring our park back to life?
义不容辞  但是要怎么修呢
It's the least I can do! But how?
等一下
Wait a minute.
我的名字  我的乐园  我的名字
My name. My park, my name.
葛蕾塔  如果我们集体牺牲了
Greta, if we all end up crashing to our collective deaths,
现在我想对你说
I just want you to know
我为你疯狂  宝贝  为你疯狂
I burn for you, baby! I burn hot!
我对你的爱愈燃愈烈
My oven is on extra fuego!
我觉得你也很帅  史蒂夫
I think you're cute, too, Steve.
等等  她说了什么  她说了什么
Wait, what? What did she say? What did she say?
齿轮
The gears.
妈妈  你不只是把我的名字写在这上面
Mom, you weren't writing over the clocks,
你是在告诉我解决办法啊
you were telling me how to fix it.
怎样启动时钟让它重获生机
How to jumpstart the clocks back to life!
写我的名字
Write my name!
按照我名字的形状来做吸管来转动齿轮
Turn the gears by writing my name!
齿轮  大家坚持住
The gears! Hold on, everybody!
成功了  成功了
It's working, it's working!
-不  -小心
- Oh, no! - Watch it!
坚持住
Hold on!
小心
Look out!
继续做
Keep going!
上上上  我们要做个U
Go, go, go! We need the "U."
欢迎来到神奇乐园
Welcome to Wonderland!
往右  往右
Now right, right!
海狸双胞胎兄弟  出动
Beaver twin brothers, activate!
尾巴打脸大法
Tail to the face!
好  再做个N  快点
Okay, now the "N." Hurry!
把我发射出去  葛蕾塔
Launch me, Greta.
-把你发射出去  -发射我
- Launch you? - Launch me.
为了神奇乐园  为了葛蕾塔
For Wonderland! For Greta!
为了自由
For freedom!
搞定
Nailed it.
我们搞定了  琼
We got this, June.
准备好了吗
You ready?
跳
Jump!
看  乐园重获生机了
Look, the park! It's coming back to life!
拍拍尾巴  库珀
Tail slap, Cooper!
太棒了  干得漂亮
Well done! A cracking job!
你真是太棒啦
You're splendiferous!
看看是哪个神奇猩猩回来了
Aw, look who's back to being WonderChimps.
跳个舞  跳个舞
Do a little dance. Do your little dance.
跳个小神奇猩猩之舞
Do your little WonderChimp dance.
看看他们多可爱
Look how cute they are!
来吧布莫  客人在等着我们呢
Come on, Boomer. There's guests to welcome.
我们要重建乐园  还要照顾客人
And things to build. And people to take care of.
完全正确
Quite right.
现在我们已经找回了团队纽带
And now that we've got our glue back,
我们将一往直前
nothing can stop us.
我  团队纽带  不  我不是
Me? The glue? No, I'm not the glue.
你才是团队纽带  葛蕾塔
You're the glue, Greta.
你一直都是
You always have been.
-是不是  兄弟们  -没错
- Isn't that right, gang? - Yeah!
你们好暖
Aw, you guys.
来吧  我们去播撒一些奇迹
Come on, let's go spread some wonder!
-对  我们就这么做  -我先来
- Yeah, that's how we do it. - Me first!
等等
Wait.
你呢  琼  你呢
What about you, June? Yeah, what about you?
我想我该回家了
Well, I probably should be getting home.
你要走了  没有你我们可怎么办
You're leaving? What are we gonna do without you?
你们就像往常一样
You're gonna do what you always do.
来  聚过来
Come on, bring it in.
在这里你们应有尽有
You have everything you need right here.
因为我们是谁
Because who are we?
我们是神奇乐园的奇迹
We are the wonder in Wonderland.
大点声
I can't hear you!
我们是神奇乐园的奇迹
We are the wonder in Wonderland.
再来一次
One more time!
我们是神奇乐园的奇迹
We are the wonder in Wonderland!
现在去接待客人吧
Now fall out.
欢迎
Welcome!
男孩儿  今天会是开心的一天
Boy, it's gonna be a great day.
我们开始吧
Let's do this thing!
准备好了
Good to go.
等着
Wait for it...
哒哒
Ta-da!
黑暗
The Darkness.
还在那儿
It's still there.
也许它永远不会消失
Maybe it'll never really fully go away.
也许它的存在是为了提醒我们
Maybe it's there to remind us
去看看我们身边的光芒
to look at the light that surrounds us.
请享受我们最新的景点  弯曲吸管滑梯
Please enjoy our newest attraction, Bendy Straw Slide,
我个人在极端条件下进行了安全测试
which I have personally safety tested under extreme conditions.
说到你身边的光
Speaking of the light that surrounds you...
史蒂夫
Steve!
你来了
Ah, here we are.
来吧  你可以请我吃爆米花
Come on, I'll let you buy me some popcorn.
好的  我马上来  我只要
Yep, I'll be right there! I just need to... Well...
等我的心跳平复下来
Wait for my heart to settle.
你会在风中听到我的声音
You'll hear me in the wind.
我知道
Oh, I know I will.
我们会在这里等你的  永远
And we'll be here for you. Always.
你好  皮纳特
Hey, Peanut!
这地方真是太美了
This place really is splendiferous!
是啊
Yep.
真是太棒了
Splendiferous!
我们有芦笋  菠菜  甘蓝
We got asparagus, spinach, brussels...
啊  你在这儿  我隐藏的最爱
Ah, there you are, my hidden sweet.
老爸
Dad!
小琼琼
June Bug?
琼  你没事吧  你怎么了
June, are you okay? What happened to you?
我很抱歉我没告诉你去哪儿
I'm so sorry for being gone a whole night
并且消失了一整晚
and not telling you where I was.
什么  我半个小时前刚把你
What? I just dropped you off at
送去数学夏令营
Math Camp 30 minutes ago.
别在意
Never mind.
如果你回来是因为担心我
If you did this because you're worried about me...
什么  担心你
Worry? About you?
你又没事
You're fine!
实际上  你是太棒了
Actually, you're awesome.
我有很多事要告诉妈妈
I have so much to tell Mom about.
琼琼
Uh, Junie...
在你把我送回数学夏令营之前
And before you bring up going back to Math Camp,
你得知道
you have to know
我是不会回去的
it's not happening.
我有很多活要干
I have way too much work to do.
-比如呢  -弥补浪费的时间
- Such as? - Making up for lost time.
那是
Is that...
邻居会喜欢的
The neighborhood will love this.
琼琼  我回来了  我买了日用品回来
Junie, I'm home! I got the rest of the supplies.
嘿  爸爸  再来一点
Hey, Dad! Just a few more...
女儿  我忙着呢  你能开下门吗
Honey, my hands are full. Can you get that?
当然  爸爸
Sure thing, Dad.
嘿  琼   我把所有横幅都挂上了
Hey June! I strung up all the banners.
接下来要做什么
What's next?
太好了  你能在后面的栅栏上
Great. Can you make a big balloon arch
搭一个越过栅栏的气球拱门吗
over the back fence?
-没问题  -谢啦
- Yep! - Thanks.
你说的越过栅栏是指
When you say over the back fence, do you mean
比栅栏高还是指在栅栏后面
over the fence, like over it, or over the fence, like behind it?
越过栅栏是指比栅栏高
Over the fence, like over it.
明白了  比栅栏高  知道了
Oh. Ding! Over the fence. Got it.
拜托请告诉班基把它放在栅栏后面就好了
Can you please tell Banky to just put it behind the fence.
我必须完成手上的工作
I got to finish.
我想你应该去开门  琼
I think you should get the door, June.
但是
Huh. But...
妈妈
Mom.
你还傻站着干什么
What are you waiting for?
快过来
Come here.
很高兴见到你
I'm glad to see you.
你是不是
Are you...
我现在没事了  小琼琼
I'm okay now, June Bug.
我也是
So am I.
看来你有保持内心的微光永远闪亮
It looks like you kept your little light shining bright.
我有一个连你都不会相信的故事
I've got a story even you might not believe.
说来听听
Try me.
这真是太美妙了
Now that is splendiferous!
嘿  齿轮秋千
Hey, Clockwork Swings!
快点  神奇乐园现在开放
Come on! Wonderland is now open!
你真是太棒了
You're splendiferous!
各位  又是在神奇乐园中的一天
Okay, everyone. It was another day in Wonderland,
世界上最棒的游乐园
the most splendiferous amusement park in the world.
皮纳特很高兴能创造一个新项目
Peanut is excited to create a new ride.
有谁能提出建议吗
Anyone have any suggestions?
有  有  我
Yes, yes, yes!
琼  琼
June! June!
班基  你有什么想法
Banky, what are you thinking?
-一个摩天轮  -这是个好主意
- A Ferris wheel! - That's a great idea.
是一个普通老式的摩天轮吗
But are we thinking just like a regular old Ferris wheel?
用荧光棒做成的摩天轮
A Ferris wheel made out of glow sticks.
会飞的摩天轮
A Ferris wheel that flies!
荧光棒制成的飞天摩天轮  这是好主意
A flying Ferris wheel made of glow sticks. That's a great idea.
我想皮纳特需要马上知道这件事
I think Peanut needs to hear about this right away.
现在  皮纳特  我们想让你做这个
Now, Peanut, here's what we want you to do.
拿着你的记号笔来创造
Take your marker and create...
太好了  真棒
That's wonderful. Wonderful.
由荧光棒做成
made out of glow sticks.
荧光棒啊
Glow sticks, huh?
听起来像是个绝妙的主意
Ooh! Sounds like a splendiferous idea!
马上就来
Coming right up!
神奇乐园